Preliminary Inventory to the League of Red Cross Societies Miscellaneous records, 1919-1922
Hoover Institution Archives
- Miscellaneous, 1919 November-December (Box 2., Folder 27)
  - Letters
    - Secretary Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 1
    - Secretary Bicknell to Pesrons, 1919 December 1 (LORCS. Statistics of membership in national Red Cross societies)
    - Strong to Olds, 1919 December 2
    - Olds to Fitzgerald, 1919 December 3 (Miss Fitzgerald's departure from the ARC to join LORCS)
    - Secretary Bicknell to Rappard, 1919 December 4
  - Memorandum - Payson to Persons, 1919 December 5 (Drugs for Czecho-Slovakia)
  - Letter - Bicknell to Strong, 1919 December 8 (Decision to turn over "Red Cross Tuberculosis Commission in Italy" records to the League)
  - Cable - Olds to Farrand, 1919 December 8 (Polish relief)
  - Memorandum - Payson to Persons, 1919 December 8
  - Letters
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 9
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 9 (Czecho-Slovakia. Personnel)
  - Memoranda
    - McKee to Payson, 1919 December 11
    - Payson to Williams, 1919 December 12
    - Payson to McKee, 1919 December 12
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 December 12
    - Strong to Bicknell, 1919 December 12 (ARC Tuberculosis Commission to Italy)
  - Memoranda
    - McKee to Payson, 1919 December 12
    - Payson to McKee, 1919 December 13
    - Payson to Johnson, 1919 December 13
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 December 15
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 December 15
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 16 (Czecho-Slovakia supplies)
    - Olds to Persons, 1919 December 16
  - Memorandum - Dupas to Payson, 1919 December 16
  - Letter - Bobbett to Persons, 1919 December 17
  - Memoranda
    - McKee to Payson, 1919 December 17
    - McKee to Payson, 1919 December 17
  - Letter - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 18
  - Memorandum - McKee to Payson, 1919 December 18
  - Letter - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 20 (Major Thwaite's report on typhus conditions in Bosnia and Herzegovina)
    - List-1919 December 20
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bobbett, 1919 December 22
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 23
    - Snow to Emerson, 1919 December 23 (Social hygiene)
    - Lakeman to Olds, 1919 December 23 (Czecho-Slovakia)
  - Memorandum - Keppel to Olds, 1919 December 23 (Personnel vacancies)
  - Letters
    - Lakeman to Bicknell, 1919 December 23
    - Keppel to Olds, 1919 December 26
  - Memorandum - Fitzgerald, 1919 December 26 (Attached: Outline of two possible schemes for the training of public health nurses: introductory letter to the questionnaire; and the questionnaire)
  - Letter - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 December 27
  - Memoranda
    - Payson to Dupas, 1919 December 27
    - Payson to Ivorzcek, 1919 December 29 (Introducing Mr. H. S. Wells)
    - McKee to Payson, 1919 December 29 (Commissary articles for LORCS)
    - Payson to McKee, 1919 December 30 (Prices on commissary supplies)
- News Sheet-1920 March 6 (issued by the Department of Information and Publication, LORCS) (Folder 28)
- Paget, Muriel, Lady - Missions (Folder 29)
  - Letters
    - Lakeman to Olds, 1920 April (Paget's Missions in Eastern Europe to be placed under general direction of League)
    - Olds to Lakeman, 1920 April 30 (same)
    - Emerson to Brown, 1920 December 3 (Lady Muriel Paget's Missions)
    - Mills to Gielgud, 1921 March 15 (same)
    - Pitt to Ryan, 1921 June 11 (Paget's child welfare work in the Baltic Provinces)
- Paris Office (Folder 30)
  - Memoranda
    - Allen to Olds, 1920 April 20 (Discontinuation of use of Paris Office)
    - Allen to Williams, 1920 May 4 (Paris office discontinued as of 1920 April 30)
- Frank W. Persons. Report, 1920 March 24 (Draft and final copy of report on health conditions in general, in Poland, the Ukraine, Russia, Austria, Romania, Serbia, Czecho-Slovakia, the Baltic States, Hungary, Montenegro, and Albania) (Folder 31)
- Poland (Folder 32)
  - Letters
    - Henderson to ARC, 1919 October 7 (Report of the Medical Commission of LORCS sent to Poland. Attached: Bulletin of LORCS - proofs)
    - Mills to Yowell, 1920 April 27 ($400,000 appropriation for expenditures in Poland)
  - Memorandum - Yowell to Mills, 1920 June 21 (Remittance for LORCS - Poland)
  - Letter - Yowell to Mills, 1920 September 13 (Funds from LORCS - Poland)
  - Memorandum - Mills to Murphy, 1921 January 14 (Shipments 1, 11, and 13)
  - Cable - Brown to Barge, 1921 February 21
  - Letters
    - Mills to Wells, 1921 February 25 (Shipment 1, 11, and 13)
    - Allen to Taylor, 1921 September 24 (Appropriations)
- "Pour l'Enfance et la Famille par l'Aide Sociale" (a summary report). Suite de la Fondation de la Croix-Rouge Americaine dans le 19ieme Arrondissement (Folder 33)
  - Letters
    - Hereford to Bicknell, 1919 November 10
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 10 (Alfred Kammermann and a plan for the care of war orphans)
    - Rappard to Bicknell, 1919 November 10
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 11 (ARC contribution of $500,000.00 to LORCS for typhus work)
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 11
    - Persons to Payson, 1919 November 11 (Drugs for the Czecho-Slovak government)
  - Cables-1919 November 11 (ARC relations with the League. Incoming and outgoing cables - Washington)
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 12 (Romanian Red Cross requests for assistance)
    - Strong to Bicknell, 1919 November 13 (Compensations of ARC nurses sent to Poland)
    - Strong to Bicknell, 1919 November 13
    - Bicknell to Rappard, 1919 November 13
  - Memorandum - Allen to Pedlow, 1919 November 13
  - Cable - Olds to Bicknell, 1919 November 14 ("..It is agreed in principle that for as possible program of League to be based upon report its commission to Poland and cables Licross to Davison, shall be supported by extension Amcross operation under general supervision League.")
  - Letter - Bicknell to Hereford, 1919 November 14
  - Memorandum - Allen to LORCS, 1919 November 14
  - Letters
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 14
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 14
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 14
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 14 (Romanian Red Cross)
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 14
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 14 (Appropriations)
  - Memorandum - Payson to Corbin, 1919 November 14 (Request for requisition - drugs for Czecho-Slovakia)
  - Cable - Bicknell to Olds, 1919 November 15
  - Letter - Bartlett to Strong, 1919 November 16
  - Cables
    - Farrand to Bicknell, 1919 November 17
    - Bicknell to Farrand, 1919 November 18 ("concerning League Commissioner. Most important immediate action is to select him and get him to Poland.")
  - Letters
    - Payson to Persons, 1919 November 18 (Drugs for Czecho-Slovakia)
    - Rappard to Bicknell, 1919 November 18
  - Memorandum - Allen to LORCS, 1919 November 19 (Relief for American citizens in Europe)
  - Letter - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 19
  - Cable - Persons, 1919 November 20 (Proposal of Shaw as Commissioner)
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 20
    - Persons to Strong, 1919 November 20
  - Cable - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 20
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 21
    - Strong to Bicknell, 1919 November 21 (Polish relief)
    - Bicknell to Persons, 1919 November 22
  - Cable - Farrand, 1919 November 24 (Proposal of Shaw as Commissioner)
  - Letters
    - Strong to Olds, 1919 November 24
    - Strong to Waldron, 1919 November 24
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 24
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 24
    - Persons to Payson, 1919 November 25 (Drugs for Czecho-Slovakia)
  - Memorandum - Payson to Persons, 1919 November 26 (same)
  - Letters
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 26
    - Persons to Bicknell, 1919 November 27 (Poland)
    - Joly to Strong, 1920 March 1
    - Rappard to Olds, 1920 April 13
  - Memorandum - Olds to Todd, 1920 April 15
  - Letters
    - Bojesen to Rappard, 1920 April 27
    - Rappard to Bojesen, 1920 May 3
- Preliminary League material (Folder 34)
  - Clipping - Journal de Geneve, 1918(?) ("La Croix Rouge de la Paix")
  - Speech - Davison, 1919 February 21 (an address by Henry P. Davison, chairman, Committee of Red Cross Societies (on the proposals of that Committee for a broader peacetime organization of the International Red Cross)
- Publications (Folder 35)
  - Bulletin -1919 May 15 (Bulletin of the LORCS)
  - Pamphlet-1920 April (Building Up a Red Cross Society)
  - Information bulletin-1921 March 7 (L'Unite de commandement dans la lutte contre la souffrance en Europe: La Ligue des Societes de la Croix-Rouge en accepte la responsabilite)
  - New items-1922 February 1 ("The following items, collected by the League of Red Cross Societies, are transmitted to those societies by way of supplement to the information and news published under the title of "The Peace Work of the Red Cross" in the January issue of Vers la Sante)
  - Circulars
    - 1922 February 17 ("The following notes are issued by the League of Red Cross Societies for the information of member societies and they are to be considered as supplementary to the notes published in the January edition of The World's Health, under the title "Red Cross in Peace")
    - 1922 March 6 (same as above except the notes are supplementary to those published in the February edition)
    - No. 3, 1922 March 22 (same as above, except the notes are supplementary to those published in the March edition)
    - No. 5, 1922 May (same as above, except the notes are supplementary to those published in the May edition)
    - Supplement to No. 5, 1922 May 13 (Junior Red Cross Bulletin)
  - Letter - Sand to Bicknell, 1922 June 23 (Information supplement)
- Publicity (Folder 36)
  - News release - W. Wilson to Davison, 1919 May 13 ("Permit me to congratulate you and your associates representing the Red Cross Societies of the United States, Great Britain, France, Italy and Japan upon the formation of the League of Red Cross Societies designed to unite the Red Cross societies of the world in active cooperation against the miseries which arise from disease and disaster)
  - Letter - Scarborough to Emerson, 1920 April 14 (Securing non-scientific publicity for the LORCS)
- Ryan, Edward W., Dr., American Red Cross Commissioner for Western Russia (Folder 37)
  - Letters
    - Ryan to Brown, 1920 January 5 (Funds for Russia)
    - Brown to Ryan, 1920 December 24. Soviet Relief Committee. Joint Distribution Committee - an American Jewish organization
    - Ryan to Brown, 1920 January 17 (same)
    - Brown to Ryan, 1921 January 26 (same)
    - Ryan to Brown, 1921 February 1
    - Bicknell to Ryan, 1921 October 25 (League Personnel)
    - Gielgud to Ryan, 1922 May 17 (Scheduled visit to Scandinavia, the Baltic States, and Poland)
    - Ryan to Olmsted, 1922 June 7 (International Public Health Nursing courses)
- Supreme Economic Council (Folder 38)
  - Memoranda
    - Supreme Economic Council
    - 1919 May 26 (Health conditions in southern and Eastern Europe)
  - Cable - Hereford to Mumford, 1919 May 29 (Request for founder members and newly invited members to join in the battle against typhus in Eastern and Southeastern Europe)
  - Memorandum-1919 May 30 (meeting with the Economic Council
  - Letter - Rappard to Thompson, 1920 March 13 (typhus conditions in Russia)
- Swiss Commission. Tuberculosis Relief. American Red Cross (Folder 39)
  - Letters
    - Mills to Roberts, 1920 June 7 (Final liquidation of tuberculosis activities in Berne)
    - Roberts to Mills, 1920 June 12 (Commission Centrale Suisse)
  - Voucher - Lutz(?) to Mills, 1920 June 14 (Fund for Commission Centrale Suisse)
  - Letters
    - Roberts to Mills, 1920 July 5 (Audit Commission Centrale Suisse)
    - Brown to Mills, 1920 July 17
    - Mills to Brown, 1920 July 20 (Swiss Commission's Tuberculosis Relief Fund)
  - Memoranda
    - Mills to Olds, 1920 July 26 (same)
    - Olds to Mills, 1920 July 27 (donation to the LORCS)
  - Letters
    - Mills to Brown, 1920 July 29 (same)
    - Brown to Mills, 1920 August 3 (same)
    - Mills to Roberts, 1920 August 7 (Swiss Commission Tuberculosis Relief)
- Transportation Department (Danzig) (Folder 40)
  - Letter - Brown to Lakeman, 1921 May 7